# Richard W. Bates

<u>richwbates@gmail.com</u> | (908) 864-7921 | Hillsborough, NJ https://github.com/richwb/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/richardwbates

# **Summary of Qualifications:**

Information technology professional with four years of enterprise level experience in Tier 1, 2, and 3 customer and internal support on a large range of projects. Worked in an Agile SDLC environment, performing quality assurance testing using SQL Management Studio, PowerShell, Team Foundation Server, and other integrated tools. Experienced in troubleshooting CDMA technology related issues and assisting customers with website and email related issues.

Focused Full Stack JavaScript Web Developer with experience including configuring my personal web server using AWS, Nginx, Node.JS, React.JS, and MongoDB/MySQL.

## **Skills:**

JavaScript, AWS, Node.js, React.js, MySQL, MongoDB, jQuery, CSS, Bootstrap, Git, Github, Firebase, Windows Server 2008R2, Windows Server 2012, Remedy, Bash, Basic Linux Knowledge, Nginix, Joomla CMS

## **Certifications:**

CompTIA Network + April 2017

# **Work Experience:**

# **My Corporate Hosting Solutions**

Sept 2017 -Present

Systems Technician

- Provide tier 1 and 2 customer support to a diverse client base for web and email support
- Website hosting and design

#### Verizon Wireless (Judge Group) - Branchburg, NJ

Nov 2015 -July 2017

Business/Systems Analyst I, Network Security - Identity Access Management

- Worked within a SDLC/Agile environment implementing software for a centralized physical identity access control across 214 sites and 125 server 2008/2016 servers nation wide
- Analyzed existing system's databases to retrieve personnel information to be implemented into the new system.
- Use case quality assurance testing for software features and bug fixed
- Tracked and resolved user and system issues using Remedy and Team Foundation Server
- Primary responsibilities include coordination configuration, deployment, and supporting the vendors in the installation of new software for equipment upgrades at 200+ locations
- Developed PowerShell scripts to expedite deployment of server configurations

#### Merck (Atlas) - Rahway, NJ

March-Nov 2015

Analyst, e-Discovery

- Archived Electronically Stored Information (ESI) for permanent data storage
- Maintained electronic data documentation by processing information requests.
- Assisted with workflow review projects to keep up to date with corporate policies and quality time management.

# Verizon Wireless (Judge Group) - Bedminster, NJ

April 2014 - Feb 2015

**Network Technician** 

- Tier 3 customer support technician troubleshooting system performance issues for 4G/LTE, 3G, and 1x wireless networks in a CDMA environment
- Responsible for investigating and reporting network reliability issues by working with customers, System Performance Engineers and the NOCC to discover and resolve network related errors

### **My Corporate Hosting Solutions**

Aug - Dec 2014

Systems Technician

- Migrated 166 websites to new systems
- Assisted customers with website hosting and email issues

# **Education**

# County College of Morris, Randolph, NJ

**Dec 2009** 

A.A.S. Telecommunications – Information Technology

# Sussex County Community College - Newton, NJ

July 2011

A.S. Liberal Arts

# Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey - New Brunswick, NJ

Jan 2018

JavaScript Full Stack Web Development